<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>#/share</title>
    <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on #/share</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:00:24 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rafaeldutra.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud Onboard</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/training/google/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:00:24 -0300</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/training/google/cloud/</guid>
      <description> Cloud Onboard is an event designed to technical business professionals. The content was designed to IT professionals, System Engineers and Operational Professionals, Developers and Solutions Architects that are searching for cloud solutions or are new using Google Cloud.
Agenda  Module 1  Google Cloud Platform introduction  Module 2  Starting to work with GCP Hierarchical Resources at GCP Profiles and access management (IAM) Interactions with GCP Cloud Launcher  Module 3: Virtual Machines at Google Cloud Platform  Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) Network Compute Engine Operations and tools  Module 4: Storage at Google Cloud Platform  Cloud Storage Cloud Big Table Cloud SQL and Cloud Spanner Cloud Datastore Comparing storage options Integrations with other resources  Module 5: Containers at Google Cloud Platform  Containers introduction Kubernetes Kubernetes Engine Cloud Datastore  Module 6: Applications at Google Cloud Platform  Google App Engine Google App Engine default environment Google App Engine flexible environment Google Cloud Endpoints and Apigee Edge  Module 7: Development, implementation and monitoring  Cloud implementation Infrastructure as code Monitoring: proactive instrumentation  Module 8: Big Data &amp;amp; Machine Learning  Google Cloud Big Data Google Cloud Machine Learning   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/training/puppet/fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 22:34:24 -0300</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/training/puppet/fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>In the training, the studens will learn to manage infrastructure in the right way. They will learn the best pratices and use Puppet to write classes and modules, in addition to using existents modules. The learning is to use a production environment workflow infrastructure, using source control management with git exhaustively.
Agenda  Fundamental components of Puppet Enterprise (and Puppet Open Source). Using Puppet on Linux and Windows. Fundamental conceps of the language and modeling of Puppet, like:  Modules and classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 17:20:29 -0300</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/mini/</guid>
      <description>DevOps culture enthusiast and IT specialist with infrastructure as code and automation focus, always believing that exists a better way to resolve problems, from the simple ones to complex ones, but mainly, knows that right way is the better way.
Has 13 years of IT experience acting as SysAdmin Linux.
Currently lives at Porto Alegre/RS and studies Security Information in UNISINOS.
Listens to Heavy Metal and other variations and likes to help who wants to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 12:54:24 -0300</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/downloads/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m leaving here some pages and downloads to see what I do.
You will see different page versions, each one of them with more or less informations due to the tools and links mentioned on the page.
So, feel free to reach me at social networks, or, directly at: raffaeldutra@gmail.com
 English
 Resume
 Mini Currículum
 Download PDF format Download DOC format  Portuguese
 Resume
 Mini Currículum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 12:54:24 -0300</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Docker Workshop - FOSS Day 2018 Fossday - Lajeado - 2018/05/05  First workshop presented about how to use Docker in a &amp;ldquo;minimum way&amp;rdquo; Dockerfile Volumes Docker Compose  Slides  Configuration Management Poatek - Porto Alegre - 2017/10/03 Brief introduction of how we can use Puppet to managem things.
 Changing granulatiry Imutable environment What is the real motive to use configuration management  Slides  Introduction to Puppet AGCO Canoas - Canoas - 2017/09/02 The ideia is to show how we can delivery better environments using patterns and same environment reproduction, having change management with confiability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/about/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/about/me/</guid>
      <description>My name is Rafael Dutra and I&amp;rsquo;m a nice guy. I was born at 29&amp;frasl;01 from some year and I&amp;rsquo;m a Sysadmin and DevOps enthusiast.
Currently I&amp;rsquo;m living at Porto Alegre/RS but I&amp;rsquo;m from Lajeado/RS and I lived my whole life at Estrela/RS, that is 120km far from Porto Alegre/RS.
I&amp;rsquo;m single and really love video games, mainly RPG and FPS and I have some games that I bring with to me until this day, like Chrono Cross, Final Fantasy VIII e IX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Introduction</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/blog/2017/02/27/docker-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/blog/2017/02/27/docker-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-docker&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Docker?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By definition on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.com/resources/what-docker&#34;&gt;https://opensource.com/resources/what-docker&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker is a tool designed to make it easier to create, deploy, and run applications by using containers. Containers allow a developer to package up an application with all of the parts it needs, such as libraries and other dependencies, and ship it all out as one package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/experience/</guid>
      <description>Experiência Segue abaixo um pouco do que fiz em cada área atuando desde 2005, quando era estagiário em uma escola particular do RS.
Reverse proxy e cache Utilizei Varnish Cache e Squid e com proxy reverso Nginx
Domínios Atuei sustentando controladores de domínio com SAMBA c/ integração LDAP em alguns projetos.
Containers Utilizo Docker desde 2015&amp;frasl;1, alguns projetos realizados mas nenhum em total produção até o momento.
Utilizei em sua maioria para pipelines em ferramentas de CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rafael Dutra</title>
      <link>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>raffaeldutra@gmail.com (Rafael Dutra)</author>
      <guid>https://rafaeldutra.me/page/cv/resume/</guid>
      <description>Brazilian, single.
Porto Alegre/RS
Email: raffaeldutra@gmail.com
Personal Statement 13+ years of experience in Information Technology, Network Administration, Infrastructure analysis, working especially with GNU/Linux.
3+ years working with PHP development and frameworks (Laravel and Codeigniter), Vagrant, Bower, Composer and Git.
In the last 2 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working mainly on Infrastructure automation (Infra as Code) and containerization with Docker.
Work Experience Jive Software (https://jivesoftware.com) Jive Software is now a part of Aurea Company (https://aurea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>